<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Akhil Sankar</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2025-01-04T15:02:06+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Akhil Sankar</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/02/introduction/"/>
   <updated>2023-11-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/02/introduction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;My name is Akhil and I am a software engineer with a background in mechanical engineering. I am primarily experienced in backend engineering  but am interested in transitioning to software engineering opportunities in motion planning, control and their practical implementation on embedded platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am therefore currently pursuing an MS with the Rutgers University Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, specializing in Systems &amp;amp; Control&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Over the past nine years, I have worked as a software engineer at different layers of the tech stack (from writing bare metal device drivers to supporting cloud orchestration) in the IoT sector. Most recently, I worked as a Robotics Software Engineer with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opshelf.com/&quot;&gt;OpenShelf&lt;/a&gt;, testing a variety of sensor integrations and developing an AWS hosted MQTTS bidirectional telemetry pipeline to remotely monitor and control the physical prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;As a side quest, I’m interested in how physical phenomena can be rendered and simulated through software. I am currently working on a simple 2D game physics engine (courtesy of the fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://pikuma.com/courses/game-physics-engine-programming&quot;&gt;Pikuma course&lt;/a&gt; on the subject). If you’re interested, you can check out this project (and some other ones) over in the &lt;a href=&quot;projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;P.S. I love making new friends. Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/akhilsankar/&quot;&gt;ping me&lt;/a&gt; if you ever feel like a coffee and a chat :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
